Hello and welcome to Real easyy English, the podcast where we have real conversations in easy English to help you understand I'm Neil and I'm Becca find
A video of this podcast with subtitles on our website BBClearningenglish.com. .
Hi Becca how are you I'm really well Thank you Neil how about yourself I'm okay but I wish it was sunny me too
At the moment it's really horrible and rainy in the UK but we're going to talk about sunny weather to make us happy
I'm glad I'm happy that's the topic today do you like sunny weather Of course I love sunny weather I think everyone loves.
A little bit of sunshine, it's good for you Yes, absolutely, so what do you like to do when the weather is sunny when the weather is sunny I.
Try to spend as much time as I can outside, so I try to wake up earlier to see the sun.
Um, and I really enjoy walking, riding my bike, going to the beach, and I will try to stay out for the whole day.
Especially if the sky is clear because then we'll have a beautiful sunset absolutely wow, I can picture all of this.
In the summer in the UK we're lucky because it's light really late and so you can do things outside in the evening Yes, you have a very long day.
In in the British summer days,, yeah, but you can have too much sun.
And of course, the sun can be dangerous so do you do anything to protect yourself from the sun
I unfortunately don't enjoy wearing sunglasses,
But I know that they're a very good precaution for you so a good way to kind of protect yourself, protect your eyes from the sun I don't really enjoy wearing hats.
Either the only thing that I do that I actually do most days even when it's not sunny is where sunscreen yes,
That's a very good idea because my my face is very important so I need to protect protect your skin so sunscreen or sun cream
Is stuff that you put on your face on your skin, arms, legs body to protect the skin from the sun Yes and it's very important.
That if you are going out on a sunny day that you put sunscreen on every part of your skin that will be under the sun because if you forget
A certain area then you might get burnedt Yes and sunburn is horrible it's really not very comfortable is it No do you sit in the shade
When it's really sunny so the shade is the darker part of outside maybe a tree or something is in the way?
Of the sun and you can sit in the shade of a tree Yes, I do enjoy sitting in the shade of trees usually
When you go to the park there will be the kind of more shady areas when it's sunny it's really nice sometimes to go to the coast
The coast is the part of the land that meets the sea so there might be a beach there.
Or cliffs or but the coast is that part of land and sea Me Yes, yeah, and cliffs are really lovely to go and have a walk on.
They're usually quite high up from the sea level, so you get really beautiful views of the rest of the coast, I love going to the coast.
Time now for a recap of the vocabulary that we've heard in this episode, starting with the wordCl.
If we say something is clear, we mean that there is nothing in the way, so a clear sky means there are no clouds in the way and you can see the sun, the sun is bright.
Our next word is shade and shade happens when something blocks the sun, for example, a tree.
Now under the tree there will be a darker, cooler area where it's nice to go and relax and get out of the hot sun and we heard sunscreen or sun
Cream that's something you rub on your skin.
So that you protect yourself from the sun so you don't get burnt and the last word we have is coast now the coast is the place where the land meets the sea and sometimes you'll see a beach there.
That's it for this episode of Real easyy English but don't forget we have a worksheet so you can test yourself on the language you learn today, it's atbblearningenglish.com. .
And we'll be back next week with another conversation in Ey English we'll see you then goodbye.